Ben A. Gertz

me@bgertz.com · bgertz.com

EDUCATION

Tulane University, New Orleans, Louisiana **B.S., Cell and Molecular Biology and Computer Science Coordinate Major**

GPA: 3.34 CS Major GPA: 3.72

Class of 2020

SUMMARY

A highly reliable, detail-oriented software development student with experience in the agile development of cloud-hosted systems using both Node.js and Ruby on Rails. Possesses local experience in using object-oriented programming in Java and Python as well as familiarity with Neo4j relational databases. Utilizes strong interpersonal skills to effectively communicate with managers and collaborate with coworkers. Employed the Microsoft Bot Framework in Node.js to build and manage an Azure-hosted natural language processing chat bot for the Microsoft Teams application. A fast learner and team player ready to contribute to the overall success of a company.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, rMark Bio, Chicago, Illinois Capstone Collaboration, rMark Bio, Chicago, Illinois Software Development Intern, rMark Bio, Chicago, Illinois June 2020 - Present August 2019 - May 2020 May 2019 - August 2019

- Developing a test suite using Test Café in Javascript for CI/CD product pipeline
- Built a recommendation engine for speaker programs using social media analytics algorithms to analyze a Neo4j graph
- Developed a chat bot using the MS Bot Framework and the LUIS natural language understanding engine for a new way to interact with rMark APIs
- Built a RESTful API test harness using the Jest JavaScript testing framework

Genetics Research Intern, Sackler School of Medicine, Tel- Aviv University, Tel- Aviv, Israel

June - August 2018

- Raised and performed experiments on USPC-1 and 2 human ovarian cancer cells
- Results showed a correlation between exposure to IGF-1 and Insulin and expression of a gene responsible for the over production of estrogen, a cause of ovarian cancer

Camp Counselor, Olin Sang Ruby Union Institute, Oconomowoc, Wisconsin

June - August 2017

- Leveraged organizational and conflict mitigation skills to provide an engaging and safe summer camp experience
- Organized and led a 900 person all camp multi-charity service day

CAMPUS INVOLVEMENT

Lab Intern, Tulane Department of Computer Science, New Orleans, Louisiana

August 2018 - March 2019

- Contributed to a web-based tool for the implementation of a researcher's algorithm to determine the likelihood of whether a sequence of amino acids within a protein would be useful in vaccine development
- Employed the Python language using the Dash framework for graphical analysis and presentation

Campus Legislative Coordinator, Tulane Israel Political Action Committee, New Orleans

May 2018 - May 2019

Secretary, Tulane Israel Political Action Committee, New Orleans, Louisiana

April 2017 - April 2018

- Maintained relationships with local congressmen and senators to inform them on key issues regarding the American-Israeli relationship
- Created and published calendars of events and general meetings

Brother, Alpha Epsilon Pi Fraternity, Tau Upsilon Chapter

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Computer: Agile, Git, Java, Python, C, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, Azure, Mac and Linux terminal
- Language: Spanish (intermediate verbal, reading and writing)

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

• Intro to Computer Science I (Python and fundamental concepts), Intro to Computer Science II (Java and OOP, C, Haskell), Systems and Networking (OS fundamentals and IP), Discrete Math, Algorithms, Software Studios (Agile webhosted development), Advanced Networking